A Guide to the Abraham Ribicoff Papers 1980.0043
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Abraham Ribicoff Papers
1958-1979
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1980.0043
5.25 Linear Feet 21 boxes of microfilm
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition
The microfilm was donated to the University of Connecticut by Patti Aronsson, presumably at the direction of Mr. Ribicoff, as they were closing down his Senate office in Washington, D.C. in 1980.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically on 21 reels of microfilm. Series I: Newsclippings, 1958-1979
Biography
Abraham Alexander Ribicoff was born in New Britain, Connecticut, on April 9, 1910. He attended New York University and graduated from the University of Chicago Law School and was admitted to the bar in 1933. Ribicoff served as a member of the Connecticut General Assembly (1938-1942), a judge of Hartford Police Court (1941-1943, 1945-1947), chairman of the assembly of municipal court judges for the State of Connecticut (1941-1942), a member of the Charter Revision Commission of the city of Hartford (1945-1946) and hearing examiner, Connecticut Fair Employment Practices Act (1937-1939). He was elected to the U.S. House of Representatives as a Democrat to the Eighty-first and Eighty-second Congresses (January 3, 1949-January 3, 1953). He was not a candidate for renomination in 1952 and was unsuccessful for election to fill a vacancy in the United States Senate. Ribicoff served as Governor of Connecticut from 1955 until 1961, when he was sworn in as Secretary of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare in the Cabinet of President John F. Kennedy. Ribicoff's political career continued with his electiond to the United States Senate in 1962, serving from January 3, 1963, to January 3, 1981. During his Senate career, he was chairman, Committee on Government Operations (Ninety-fourth and Ninety-fifth Congresses) and Committee on Governmental Affairs (Ninety-fifth and Ninety-sixth Congresses). Abraham Ribicoff died on February 22, 1998.
Existence and location of originals
The original scrapbooks of newsclippings documenting Mr. Ribicoff's career are located at the Library of Congress>.
Scope and content note
The collection contains 21 reels of microfilm containing newsclippings of Senator Ribicoff's Gubernatorial and Senate careers. The reels that are numbered sequentially (1-20) contains scrapbooks of newsclippings kept throughout the Senator's senate career (1962-1979). Reel 21, "personality News" are newsclippings from Ribicoff's term as Governor of Connecticut (1958-1961). A poster from Mr. Ribicoff's run for Senate can be found in Series II of the Connecticut Political Collections, also in Archives & Special Collections.
Politicians; Clippings (information artifacts); Ribicoff, Abraham, 1910-1988
- Series I: Newsclippings, 1958-1979
  - 1963 January - June (Reel 1)
  - 1963 July - December (Reel 2)
  - 1964 (Reel 3)
  - 1965 January - June (Reel 4)
  - 1965 July - December (Reel 5)
  - 1966 January - April (Reel 6)
  - 1966 May - December (Reel 7)
  - 1967 (Reel 8)
  - 1968 January - June (Reel 9)
  - 1968 July - October (Reel 10)
  - 1968 November - 1969 December (Reel 11)
  - 1970-1971 (Reel 12)
  - 1972 (Reel 13)
  - 1973 (Reel 14)
  - 1974 January - November (Reel 15)
  - 1975 (Reel 16)
  - 1977 January - October (Reel 17)
  - 1977 November - 1978 August, 1978 December (Reel 18)
  - 1978 August - September (Reel 19)
  - 1979 January - April (Reel 20)
  - 1958, 1960-1961 (Reel 21)